Contact

massiely@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/massieleversley-mj-rn-5b6196128 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Ambulatory Care
Team Management
Management

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Internal Medicine Residency Nursing Award

Excellence in Nursing Award
National Environmental Leadership
Award

Partners in Excellence Award - Optimizing Collaboration

Partners in Excellence Award - Advancing Innovation & Progress

Massiel Eversley MJ, RN

Regional Nurse Director at Brigham and Women's Hospital Greater Boston Area

Summary

Nurse leader with 13+ years of experience in the healthcare industry with unique skill set and education. Experience in healthcare strategy, management, primary care, pediatrics, adult care, patient/ staff education, home/community health; grant programs, policy and case management. Highly effective in various leadership roles of Nurse Director, Case Manager, and Charge Nurse. Mentor, coach and educator to residents, administrative/clinical staff, and nurses. Special interests in serving the needs of vulnerable populations, social determinants of health, and public health. Honored with several awards for education/teaching, commitment to patient care, and chronic disease management.

Experience

Brigham and Women's Hospital 7 years

Regional Nurse Director October 2017 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Primary Care- Jen Center, BCMA, FCA,Longwood, Transition Clinic,South Huntington

Regional nurse leader responsible for strategic planning and providing nursing clinical / administrative oversight for all Primary Care clinics in Region 1 and the Primary Care float pool. Provide oversight, mentoring and coaching to RN Flow Managers, nurses/other staff who are direct reports. Function in a collaborative leadership triad model in partnership with the regional medical director and regional administrator.

Nurse Director

August 2013 - October 2017 (4 years 3 months)

Primary Care / Family Care Associates

Provide hands on nursing and clinic leadership at a family practice/ resident clinic serving adults and children of all ages and diverse cultural backgrounds with various social needs. Support the clinic's mission of providing team based/medical home approach to patient care through training of staff.

Develop effective workflows through PDSA cycle trials in order to develop effective and productive workflows that meet patient needs. Keep practice up to date and compliant with regulatory requirements in order to prepare for Joint Commission, laboratory, and DPH audits. Conduct chart and direct observation audits as a learning tool for staff while ensuring the highest quality of care is provided. Manage the Department of Public Health Vaccine for Children Program and clinic medication inventory and ordering. Organize, supervise, coach and evaluate the work of clinical staff. Develop and administer policies, procedures, and utilize current concepts of nursing practice to drive work flow and care in the practice. Provide effective leadership to staff through clinical supervision, timely feedback, and transparency. Recruit, hire, train and provide clinical supervision to Administrative, Medical Assistant and Nursing staff on all aspects of patient care. Provide direct patient care such as vaccine administration, patient education, case management and telephone triage. Implemented RN billable visits and opened clinic lab. Act as Error Reporting Manager and follow up on all incident reports in my department. Make budget conscious decisions that align with goals of the department. Report to the Associate Chief Nurse and collaborate with leadership triad of medical director and practice managers. Collaborate with other nursing leadership in development of CPG and Department protocols. Work closely with clinic and hospital leadership to ensure effective processes are in place to meet the needs of the patient population.

Boston Senior Home Care
Registered Nurse Contractor
April 2016 - August 2017 (1 year 5 months)
Boston, MA

Worked with the Personal Care Attendant team to assess client care needs and implement appropriate service plans for the enrolled clients. Conducted home visits, evaluated care needs and implemented appropriate service plans. Maintained collaborative relationships with agencies and institutions that serve BSHC clients. Stayed up to date with insurance standards and regulations in order to provide adequate services to consumers.

Best Doctors
Member Advocate / Case Manager
November 2012 - July 2013 (9 months)
Boston, MA

Main responsibilities were to help lead a cross-functional clinical team of coordinators, physicians, and nurses in order to provide the best quality service to members through all service lines. Managed up to 65 cases at a time, each case lasting an average of 6 weeks. Cases were of diverse clinical nature ranging from pediatric failure to thrive cases to breast cancer cases. Supported the Ask the Expert line by writing clinical vignettes based on member symptoms to be utilized by external physicians to create reports. Obtained comprehensive health histories through a dynamic intake assessment in order to capture all relevant clinical data on their current condition in order for experts and physicians to formulate an expert medical second opinion. Decided what medical records were to be collected for each clinical case. Provided clinical leadership, support and guidance to nonnursing staff of clinical coordinators during all stages of case development. Collaborated and consulted with physicians during all stages of a case. Took live triage calls and direct members to appropriate services as needed. Managed all cases and teams remotely the majority of the time. Served members in the US as well as International members in Mexico, India, and those that only spoke Spanish.

Boston Children's Hospital 6 years 2 months

Nurse Case Manager / Staff Nurse II May 2009 - November 2012 (3 years 7 months)

Community Asthma Initiative

Through a quality improvement focused intervention worked with the high risk and underserved pediatric asthma population by providing home visits, case management, and education on medications, self-advocacy, plan of care, and trigger reduction. Handled a caseload of 75 new patients per year and follow them for over two years. Partnered with their medical home, specialists, schools and community resources to develop patient centered plans to reduce asthma-related hospitalizations and emergency department visits. Contributed to city wide collaborative efforts in partnership of DPH to standardize asthma home visits by implementing new systems and providing community health worker clinical supervision and training as new programmatic phases were initiated. Contributed in the development and execution of quality improvement initiatives related to patient communication, engagement, system innovations, and electronic documentation. Active member of the BCH Legislative Action Interest Group.

Staff Nurse I / Charge Nurse

October 2006 - May 2009 (2 years 8 months)

Plastics/ Urology / Orthpedics

Worked on an 11 bed Urology/Plastics unit with patients undergoing procedures such as repair of cleft lip / palate, lymphatic malformations, urethral re-implants and Le Forte procedures. Collaborated care of patients with medical team and parents, educated families on conditions and care, and conducted care according to policy and procedure. Performed duties of Charge Nurse Facilitator, conducted quality improvement audits, and was a unit based Mock Code Facilitator. Served as a Safety Event Reporting System Manager for the unit. Also worked in 36 bed orthopedic unit caring for patients undergoing procedures ranging from minor procedures such as bowel preparations to major surgeries such as hip replacements and spinal fusions.

VNA of Boston
Visiting Nurse / Case Manager
December 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 1 month)
Maternal Child health

Worked with women and children from Boston communities in their homes. Performed pregnancy complications assessments and mother-baby/ postpartum assessments. Cared for premature infants and infants with feeding difficulties, failure to thrive, Narcotic Abstinence Syndrome and other illnesses after hospital discharge. Conducted home safety evaluations, reinforced parent/patient teaching, and referred families to community resources when appropriate. Reported findings to MD's and collaborated to establish the best plan of care for patients to remain safe and independent in their homes.

Education

Northeastern University
Bachelor's degree, Nursing · (2002 - 2006)

University of Colorado Boulder
Certificate, Caritas Coach Education Program · (2016 - 2016)

Loyola University Chicago Master's degree, Jurisprudence in Health Law · (2010 - 2012)